<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Episcopal Morning Prayer</string>
    <string name="header_text">Rite II Generator</string>
    <string name="clergy_prompt_text">I AM A:</string>
    <string name="clergy_first">PRIEST</string>
    <string name="clergy_second">OTHER</string>
    <string name="reading_prompt_text">I WANT TO READ:</string>
    <string name="reading_first">JUBILATE</string>
    <string name="reading_second">VENITE</string>
    <string name="reading_third">PSALM</string>
    <string name="collect_prompt_text">I WANT THE COLLECT FOR:</string>
    <string name="lesson_prompt_text">LESSON(S):</string>
    <string name="lesson_first">OLD TEST.</string>
    <string name="lesson_second">NEW TEST.</string>
    <string name="lesson_third">GOSPEL</string>
    <string-array name="collects">
        <item>SUNDAYS</item>
        <item>SATURDAYS</item>
        <item>FRIDAYS</item>
        <item>PEACE</item>
        <item>RENEWAL OF LIFE</item>
        <item>GRACE</item>
        <item>GUIDANCE</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="alleluia">Alleluia</string>
    <string name="opensent">Opening Sentences</string>
    <string name="confofsin">Confession of Sin</string>
    <string name="invandsalt">The Inventory and Psalter</string>
    <string name="psalmsappointed">The Psalm or Psalms Appointed</string>
    <string name="lesson">The Lessons</string>
    <string name="creed">The Apostles\' Creed</string>
    <string name="prayers">The Prayers</string>
    <string name="collectday">The Collect of the Day</string>
    <string name="thanksgiving">The General Thanksgiving</string>

    <string name="silencekneeling">Silence may be kept, all kneeling</string>
    <string name="silence">Silence may be kept</string>
    <string name="prieststand">The Priest alone stands and says</string>
    <string name="standorkneel">The people stand or kneel</string>
    <string name="stand">All stand</string>
    <string name="remainkneeling">Remaining Kneeling</string>
    <string name="togetherstand">Officiant and people together, all standing</string>
    <string name="togetherkneel">Officiant and people together, all kneeling</string>
    <string name="officiantandpeople">Officiant and People</string>
    <string name="officiantsays">The Officiant says to the people</string>

    <string-array name="openingadvent_chapters">
        <item>Mark 13:55, 36</item>
        <item>Isaiah 40:3</item>
        <item>Isaiah 40:5</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingadvent">
        <item>Watch, for you known not when the master of the house will come, in the evening, or at midnight, or at cockcrow, or in my morning; lest he come suddenly and find you asleep.</item>
        <item>In the wilderness prepare the way of the Lord, make straight in the desert a highway for our God.</item>
        <item>The glory of the Lord shall be revealed, and all flesh shall see it together.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingchristmas_chapters">
        <item>Luke 2:10, 11</item>
        <item>Revelation 21:3</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingchristmas">
        <item>Behold, I bring you good news of a great joy, which will come to all the people; for unto you is born this day in the city of David, a Savior, who is Christ the Lord.</item>
        <item>Behold, the dwelling of God is the mankind. He will dwell with them, and they shall be his people, and God himself will be with them, and be their God.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingepiphany_chapters">
        <item>Isaiah 60:3</item>
        <item>Isaiah 49:6b</item>
        <item>Malachi 1:11</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingepiphany">
        <item>Nations shall come to your light, and kings to the brightness of your rising.</item>
        <item>I will give you as a light to the nations, that my salvation may reach to the end of the earth.</item>
        <item>From the rising of the sun to its setting my Name shall be great among the nations, and in every place incense shall be offered to my Name, and a pure offering: for my Name shall be great among the nations, says the Lord of hosts.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openinglent_chapters">
        <item>I John 1:8, 9</item>
        <item>Joel 2:13</item>
        <item>Luke 15:18, 19</item>
        <item>Daniel 9:9, 10</item>
        <item>Mark 8:34</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openinglent">
        <item>If we say we have no sin, we deceive ourselves, and the tr uth is not in us; but if we confess our sins, God who is faithful and just, will forgive our sins and cleanse us from all unrighteousness.</item>
        <item>Rend your hearts and not your garments. Return to the Lord your God, for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love, and repents of evil.</item>
        <item>I will arise and go to my father, and I will say to him, "Father, I have sinned against heaven, and before you; I am no longer worthy to be called your son."</item>
        <item>To the Lord our God belong mercy and forgiveness, because we have rebelled against him and have not obeyed the voice of the Lord our God by following his laws which he set before us.</item>
        <item>Jesus said, "If anyone will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow me."</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingholyweek_chapters">
        <item>Isaiah 53:6</item>
        <item>Lamentations 1:12</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingholyweek">
        <item>All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the Lord has laid on him the iniquity of us all.</item>
        <item>Is it nothing to you, all you who pass by? Look and see if there is any sorrow like my sorrow which was brought upon me, whom the Lord hath afflicted.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingeasterasc_chapters">
        <item>Psalm 118:24</item>
        <item>1 Corinthians 15:57</item>
        <item>Colossians 3:1</item>
        <item>Hebrews 9:24</item>
        <item>Acts 1:8</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingeasterasc">
        <item>On this day the Lord has acted; we will rejoice and be glad in it.</item>
        <item>Thanks be to God, who gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.</item>
        <item>If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God.</item>
        <item>Christ has entered, not into a sanctuary made with hands, a copy of true one, but into heaven itself, now to appear in the presence of God on our behalf.</item>
        <item>You shall receive power when the Holy Ghost has come upon you; and you shall be my witness in Jerusalem, and in all Judea, and Samaria, and to the ends of the earth.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="openingeasterasc_pt1">Alleluia! Christ is risen.</string>
    <string name="openingeasterasc_pt2">The Lord is risen indeed. Alleluia!</string>

    <string name="revelation4_8">Revelation 4:8</string>
    <string name="openingtrinity">Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.</string>

    <string-array name="openingsaint_chapters">
        <item>Colossians 1:12</item>
        <item>Ephesians 2:19</item>
        <item>Psalm 19:4</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingsaint">
        <item>We give thanks to the Father, who has made us worthy to share in the inheritance of the saints in light.</item>
        <item>You are no longer strangers and sojourners, but fellow citizens with the saints and members of the household of God.</item>
        <item>Their sound has gone out into all lands, and their message to the ends of the world.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="psalm105_1">Psalm 105:1</string>
    <string name="openingthanksgiving">O give thanks to the Lord, and call upon his Name; make known his deeds among the peoples.</string>

    <string-array name="openinganytime_chapters">
        <item>Philippians 1:2</item>
        <item>Psalm 122:1</item>
        <item>Psalm 19:14</item>
        <item>Psalm 43:3</item>
        <item>Habakkuk 2:20</item>
        <item>John 4:23</item>
        <item>Isaiah 57:15</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openinganytime">
        <item>Grace to you and peace from God our Father and from the Lord Jesus Christ.</item>
        <item>I was glad when they said to me, "Let us go to the house of the Lord."</item>
        <item>Let the words of my mouth and the meditation of my heart be acceptable in your sight, O Lord, my strength and my redeemer.</item>
        <item>Send out your light and your truth, that they may lead me, and bring me to your holy hill and to your dwelling.</item>
        <item>The Lord is in his holy temple; let all the earth keep silence before him.</item>
        <item>The hour is coming, and now is, when the true worshipers will worship the Father in spirit and in truth, for such the Father seeks to worship him.</item>
        <item>Thus says the high and lofty One who inhabits eternity, whose name is Holy, "I dwell in the high and holy place and also with the one who has a contrite and humble spirit, to revive the spirit of the humble and to revive the heart of the contrite."</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="confessionofsin_pt1_priest">
        <item>Dearly beloved, we have come together in the presence of Almighty God our heavenly Father, to set forth his praise, to hear his holy Word, and to ask, for ourselves and on behalf of others, those things that are necessary for our life and our salvation. And so that we may prepare ourselves in heart and mind to worship him, let us kneel in silence, and with penitent and obedient hearts confess our sins, that we may obtain forgiveness by his infinite goodness and mercy.</item>
        <item>Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt2_priest">Most merciful God,&lt;br /&gt; we confess that we have sinned against you&lt;br /&gt; in thought, word, and deed,&lt;br /&gt; by what we have done,&lt;br /&gt; and by what we have left undone.&lt;br /&gt; We have not loved you with our whole heart;&lt;br /&gt; we have not loved our neighbors as ourselves.&lt;br /&gt;We are truly sorry and we humbly repent.&lt;br /&gt;For the sake of your Son Jesus Christ,&lt;br /&gt;have mercy on us and forgive us;&lt;br /&gt;that we may delight in your will,&lt;br /&gt;and walk in your ways,&lt;br /&gt;to the glory of your name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt3_priest">Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life. <i>Amen.</i></string>
    <string-array name="confessionofsin_pt1_other">
        <item>Dearly beloved, we have come together in the presence of Almighty God your heavenly Father, to set forth his praise, to hear his holy Word, and to ask, for ourselves and on behalf of others, those things that are necessary for your life and your salvation. And so that we may prepare ourselves in heart and mind to worship him, let you kneel in silence, and with penitent and obedient hearts confess your sins, that we may obtain forgiveness by his infinite goodness and mercy.</item>
        <item>Let you confess your sins against God and your neighbor.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt2_other">Most merciful God, we confess that we have sinned against you in thought, word, and deed, by what we have done, and by what we have left undone. We have not loved you with your whole heart; that we may delight in your will, and walk in your ways, to the glory of your Name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt3_other">Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through your Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life. <i>Amen.</i></string>

    <string name="invandsalt_pt1">&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;Officiant:  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Lord, open our lips.</string>
    <string name="invandsalt_pt2">&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;People:  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;And our mouth shall proclaim your praise.</string>
    <string name="invandsalt_pt3_lent">Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</string>
    <string name="invandsalt_pt3">Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Alleluia.</string>

    <string name="jubilate_title">Jubilate</string>
    <string name="psalm100">Psalm 100</string>
    <string name="jubilate">Be joyful in the Lord, all you lands;&lt;br /&gt;serve the Lord with gladness&lt;br /&gt;and come before his presence with a song.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Know this: The Lord himself is God;&lt;br /&gt;he himself has made us, and we are his;&lt;br /&gt;we are his people and the sheep of his pasture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter his gates with thanksgiving;&lt;br /&gt;go into his courts with praise;&lt;br /&gt;give thanks to him and call upon his Name.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the Lord is good;&lt;br /&gt;his mercy is everlasting;&lt;br /&gt;and his faithfulness endures from age to age.</string>
    <string name="venite_title">Venite</string>
    <string name="psalm95_1">Psalm 95:1–7</string>
    <string name="venite">Come, let us sing to the Lord;&lt;br /&gt;let us shout for joy to the Rock of our salvation.&lt;br /&gt;Let us come before his presence with thanksgiving&lt;br /&gt;and raise a loud shout to him with psalms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the Lord is a great God,&lt;br /&gt;and a great King above all gods.&lt;br /&gt;In his hand are the caverns of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;and the heights of the hills are his also.&lt;br /&gt;The sea is his, for he made it,&lt;br /&gt;and his hands have molded the dry land.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Come, let us bow down, and bend the knee,&lt;br /&gt;and kneel before the Lord our Maker.&lt;br /&gt;For he is our God,&lt;br /&gt;and we are the people of his pasture and the sheep of his hand.&lt;br /&gt;Oh, that today you would hearken to his voice!</string>

    <string name="antiphon_advent">Our King and Savior draweth nigh: O come, let us adore him.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_12daysofchristmas">Alleluia. Unto us a child is born: O Come, let us adore him. Alleluia.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_epiphanythrubaptismchristandtransfigurationandholycross">The Lord hath manifested forth his glory: O come, let us adore him.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_lent">The Lord is full of compassion and mercy: O come, let us adore him.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_eastertoasc">Alleluia. The Lord is risen indeed: O come, let us adore him. Alleluia.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_asctopentecost">Alleluia. The Lord ascendeth into heaven: O come, let us adore him. Alleluia.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_pentecost">Alleluia. The spirit of the Lord filleth the world: O come, let us adore him. Alleluia.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_trinitysunday">Father, Son, and Holy Ghost, one God: O come, let us adore him.</string>
    <string-array name="antiphon_otherdays">
        <item>The earth is the Lord\'s for he made it: O come, let us adore him.</item>
        <item>Worship the Lord in the beauty of holiness: O come, let us adore him.</item>
        <item>The mercy of the Lord is everlasting: O come, let us adore him.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="antiphon_incarnation">The Word was made flesh and dwelt among us: O come, let us adore him.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_incarnation_easter">Alleluia. The Word was made flesh and dwelt among us: O come, let us adore him. Alleluia.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_allsaints">The Lord is glorious in his saints: O come, let us adore him.</string>
    <string name="antiphon_allsaints_easter">Alleluia. The Lord is glorious in his saints: O come, let us adore him. Alleluia.</string>

    <string name="endofpsalmsappointed">Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit:&lt;br /&gt;as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</string>

    <string-array name="canticle">
        <item>I will sing to the Lord, for he is lofty and uplifted; &lt;br/&gt; the horse and its rider has he hurled into the sea. &lt;br/&gt;The Lord is my strength and my refuge; &lt;br/&gt; the Lord has become my Savior. &lt;br/&gt;This is my God and I will praise him, &lt;br/&gt; the God of my people and I will exalt him. &lt;br/&gt;The Lord is a mighty warrior; &lt;br/&gt; Yahweh is his Name. &lt;br/&gt;The chariots of Pharaoh and his army has he hurled into the sea; &lt;br/&gt; the finest of those who bear armor have been &lt;br/&gt;      drowned in the Red Sea. &lt;br/&gt;The fathomless deep has overwhelmed them; &lt;br/&gt; they sank into the depths like a stone. &lt;br/&gt;Your right hand, O Lord, is glorious in might; &lt;br/&gt; your right hand, O Lord, has overthrown the enemy. &lt;br/&gt;Who can be compared with you, O Lord, among the gods? &lt;br/&gt; who is like you, glorious in holiness, &lt;br/&gt; awesome in renown, and worker of wonders? &lt;br/&gt;You stretched forth your right hand; &lt;br/&gt; the earth swallowed them up. &lt;br/&gt;With your constant love you led the people you redeemed; &lt;br/&gt; with your might you brought them in safety to &lt;br/&gt;      your holy dwelling. &lt;br/&gt;You will bring them in and plant them &lt;br/&gt; on the mount of your possession, &lt;br/&gt;The resting-place you have made for yourself, O Lord, &lt;br/&gt; the sanctuary, O Lord, that your hand has established. &lt;br/&gt;The Lord shall reign &lt;br/&gt; for ever and for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Surely, it is God who saves me; &lt;br/&gt; I will trust in him and not be afraid. &lt;br/&gt;For the Lord is my stronghold and my sure defense, &lt;br/&gt; and he will be my Savior. &lt;br/&gt;Therefore you shall draw water with rejoicing &lt;br/&gt; from the springs of salvation. &lt;br/&gt;And on that day you shall say, &lt;br/&gt; Give thanks to the Lord and call upon his Name; &lt;br/&gt;Make his deeds known among the peoples; &lt;br/&gt; see that they remember that his Name is exalted. &lt;br/&gt;Sing the praises of the Lord, for he has done great things, &lt;br/&gt; and this is known in all the world. &lt;br/&gt;Cry aloud, inhabitants of Zion, ring out your joy, &lt;br/&gt; for the great one in the midst of you is the Holy One of Israel.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Seek the Lord while he wills to be found; &lt;br/&gt; call upon him when he draws near. &lt;br/&gt;Let the wicked forsake their ways &lt;br/&gt; and the evil ones their thoughts; &lt;br/&gt;And let them turn to the Lord, and he will have compassion, &lt;br/&gt; and to our God, for he will richly pardon. &lt;br/&gt;For my thoughts are not your thoughts, &lt;br/&gt; nor your ways my ways, says the Lord. &lt;br/&gt;For as the heavens are higher than the earth, &lt;br/&gt; so are my ways higher than your ways, &lt;br/&gt; and my thoughts than your thoughts.&lt;br/&gt;For as rain and snow fall from the heavens &lt;br/&gt; and return not again, but water the earth, &lt;br/&gt;Bringing forth life and giving growth, &lt;br/&gt; seed for sowing and bread for eating, &lt;br/&gt;So is my word that goes forth from my mouth; &lt;br/&gt; it will not return to me empty; &lt;br/&gt;But it will accomplish that which I have purposed, &lt;br/&gt; and prosper in that for which I sent it.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Arise, shine, for your light has come, &lt;br/&gt; and the glory of the Lord has dawned upon you.&lt;br/&gt;For behold, darkness covers the land; &lt;br/&gt; deep gloom enshrouds the peoples. &lt;br/&gt;But over you the Lord will rise, &lt;br/&gt; and his glory will appear upon you. &lt;br/&gt;Nations will stream to your light, &lt;br/&gt; and kings to the brightness of your dawning. &lt;br/&gt;Your gates will always be open; &lt;br/&gt; by day or night they will never be shut. &lt;br/&gt;They will call you, The City of the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; The Zion of the Holy One of Israel. &lt;br/&gt;Violence will no more be heard in your land, &lt;br/&gt; ruin or destruction within your borders. &lt;br/&gt;You will call your walls, Salvation, &lt;br/&gt; and all your portals, Praise. &lt;br/&gt;The sun will no more be your light by day; &lt;br/&gt; by night you will not need the brightness of the moon.&lt;br/&gt;The Lord will be your everlasting light, &lt;br/&gt; and your God will be your glory.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Glorify the Lord, all you works of the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever. &lt;br/&gt;In the firmament of his power, glorify the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever.&lt;br/&gt;Glorify the Lord, you angels and all powers of the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; O heavens and all waters above the heavens. &lt;br/&gt;Sun and moon and stars of the sky, glorify the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glorify the Lord, every shower of rain and fall of dew, &lt;br/&gt; all winds and fire and heat. &lt;br/&gt;Winter and Summer, glorify the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glorify the Lord, O chill and cold, &lt;br/&gt;drops of dew and flakes of snow. &lt;br/&gt;Frost and cold, ice and sleet, glorify the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glorify the Lord, O nights and days, &lt;br/&gt; O shining light and enfolding dark. &lt;br/&gt;Storm clouds and thunderbolts, glorify the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Let us glorify the Lord: Father, Son, and Holy Spirit; &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever. &lt;br/&gt;In the firmament of his power, glorify the Lord, &lt;br/&gt; praise him and highly exalt him for ever.</item>
        <item>Glory to you, Lord God of our fathers; &lt;br/&gt; you are worthy of praise; glory to you. &lt;br/&gt;Glory to you for the radiance of your holy Name; &lt;br/&gt; we will praise you and highly exalt you for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to you in the splendor of your temple; &lt;br/&gt; on the throne of your majesty, glory to you. &lt;br/&gt;Glory to you, seated between the Cherubim; &lt;br/&gt; we will praise you and highly exalt you for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to you, beholding the depths; &lt;br/&gt; in the high vault of heaven, glory to you. &lt;br/&gt;Glory to you, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit; &lt;br/&gt; we will praise you and highly exalt you for ever.</item>
        <item>O Lord and Ruler of the hosts of heaven, &lt;br/&gt; God of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, &lt;br/&gt; and of all their righteous offspring: &lt;br/&gt;You made the heavens and the earth, &lt;br/&gt; with all their vast array.&lt;br/&gt;All things quake with fear at your presence; &lt;br/&gt; they tremble because of your power. &lt;br/&gt;But your merciful promise is beyond all measure; &lt;br/&gt; it surpasses all that our minds can fathom. &lt;br/&gt;O Lord, you are full of compassion, &lt;br/&gt; long-suffering, and abounding in mercy. &lt;br/&gt;You hold back your hand; &lt;br/&gt; you do not punish as we deserve. &lt;br/&gt;In your great goodness, Lord, &lt;br/&gt;you have promised forgiveness to sinners, &lt;br/&gt; that they may repent of their sin and be saved. &lt;br/&gt;And now, O Lord, I bend the knee of my heart, &lt;br/&gt; and make my appeal, sure of your gracious goodness. &lt;br/&gt;I have sinned, O Lord, I have sinned, &lt;br/&gt; and I know my wickedness only too well. &lt;br/&gt;Therefore I make this prayer to you: &lt;br/&gt; Forgive me, Lord, forgive me. &lt;br/&gt;Do not let me perish in my sin, &lt;br/&gt; nor condemn me to the depths of the earth. &lt;br/&gt;For you, O Lord, are the God of those who repent, &lt;br/&gt; and in me you will show forth your goodness. &lt;br/&gt;Unworthy as I am, you will save me, &lt;br/&gt;in accordance with your great mercy, &lt;br/&gt; and I will praise you without ceasing all the days of my life. &lt;br/&gt;For all the powers of heaven sing your praises, &lt;br/&gt; and yours is the glory to ages of ages. Amen.</item>
        <item>My soul proclaims the greatness of the Lord, &lt;br/&gt;my spirit rejoices in God my Savior; &lt;br/&gt; for he has looked with favor on his lowly servant.&lt;br/&gt;From this day all generations will call me blessed: &lt;br/&gt; the Almighty has done great things for me, &lt;br/&gt; and holy is his Name. &lt;br/&gt;He has mercy on those who fear him &lt;br/&gt; in every generation. &lt;br/&gt;He has shown the strength of his arm, &lt;br/&gt; he has scattered the proud in their conceit. &lt;br/&gt;He has cast down the mighty from their thrones, &lt;br/&gt; and has lifted up the lowly. &lt;br/&gt;He has filled the hungry with good things, &lt;br/&gt; and the rich he has sent away empty. &lt;br/&gt;He has come to the help of his servant Israel, &lt;br/&gt; for he has remembered his promise of mercy, &lt;br/&gt;The promise he made to our fathers, &lt;br/&gt; to Abraham and his children for ever.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Blessed be the Lord, the God of Israel; &lt;br/&gt; he has come to his people and set them free. &lt;br/&gt;He has raised up for us a mighty savior, &lt;br/&gt; born of the house of his servant David. &lt;br/&gt;Through his holy prophets he promised of old, &lt;br/&gt;that he would save us from our enemies, &lt;br/&gt; from the hands of all who hate us. &lt;br/&gt;He promised to show mercy to our fathers &lt;br/&gt; and to remember his holy covenant. &lt;br/&gt;This was the oath he swore to our father Abraham, &lt;br/&gt; to set us free from the hands of our enemies, &lt;br/&gt;Free to worship him without fear, &lt;br/&gt; holy and righteous in his sight &lt;br/&gt; all the days of our life.&lt;br/&gt;You, my child, shall be called the prophet of the Most High, &lt;br/&gt; for you will go before the Lord to prepare his way, &lt;br/&gt;To give his people knowledge of salvation &lt;br/&gt; by the forgiveness of their sins. &lt;br/&gt;In the tender compassion of our God &lt;br/&gt; the dawn from on high shall break upon us, &lt;br/&gt;To shine on those who dwell in darkness and the &lt;br/&gt;      shadow of death, &lt;br/&gt; and to guide our feet into the way of peace.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Lord, you now have set your servant free &lt;br/&gt; to go in peace as you have promised; &lt;br/&gt;For these eyes of mine have seen the Savior, &lt;br/&gt; whom you have prepared for all the world to see: &lt;br/&gt;A Light to enlighten the nations, &lt;br/&gt; and the glory of your people Israel.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Splendor and honor and kingly power &lt;br/&gt; are yours by right, O Lord our God, &lt;br/&gt;For you created everything that is, &lt;br/&gt; and by your will they were created and have their being;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And yours by right, O Lamb that was slain, &lt;br/&gt; for with your blood you have redeemed for God, &lt;br/&gt;From every family, language, people, and nation, &lt;br/&gt; a kingdom of priests to serve our God.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;And so, to him who sits upon the throne, &lt;br/&gt; and to Christ the Lamb, &lt;br/&gt;Be worship and praise, dominion and splendor, &lt;br/&gt; for ever and for evermore.</item>
        <item>O ruler of the universe, Lord God, &lt;br/&gt;great deeds are they that you have done, &lt;br/&gt; surpassing human understanding. &lt;br/&gt;Your ways are ways of righteousness and truth, &lt;br/&gt;O King of all the ages.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Who can fail to do you homage, Lord, &lt;br/&gt;and sing the praises of your Name? &lt;br/&gt; for you only are the Holy One. &lt;br/&gt;All nations will draw near and fall down before you, &lt;br/&gt; because your just and holy works have been revealed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: &lt;br/&gt; as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</item>
        <item>Glory to God in the highest, &lt;br/&gt; and peace to his people on earth.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lord God, heavenly King, &lt;br/&gt;almighty God and Father,&lt;br/&gt; we worship you, we give you thanks, &lt;br/&gt; we praise you for your glory.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Lord Jesus Christ, only Son of the Father, &lt;br/&gt;Lord God, Lamb of God, &lt;br/&gt;you take away the sin of the world: &lt;br/&gt; have mercy on us; &lt;br/&gt;you are seated at the right hand of the Father: &lt;br/&gt; receive our prayer.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;For you alone are the Holy One, &lt;br/&gt;you alone are the Lord, &lt;br/&gt;you alone are the Most High,&lt;br/&gt; Jesus Christ, &lt;br/&gt; with the Holy Spirit, &lt;br/&gt; in the glory of God the Father. Amen.</item>
        <item>You are God: we praise you; &lt;br/&gt;You are the Lord; we acclaim you; &lt;br/&gt;You are the eternal Father: &lt;br/&gt;All creation worships you. &lt;br/&gt;To you all angels, all the powers of heaven, &lt;br/&gt;Cherubim and Seraphim, sing in endless praise: &lt;br/&gt; Holy, holy, holy Lord, God of power and might,&lt;br/&gt; heaven and earth are full of your glory. &lt;br/&gt;The glorious company of apostles praise you. &lt;br/&gt;The noble fellowship of prophets praise you. &lt;br/&gt;The white-robed army of martyrs praise you. &lt;br/&gt;Throughout the world the holy Church acclaims you; &lt;br/&gt; Father, of majesty unbounded, &lt;br/&gt; your true and only Son, worthy of all worship,&lt;br/&gt; and the Holy Spirit, advocate and guide.&lt;br/&gt;You, Christ, are the king of glory, &lt;br/&gt;the eternal Son of the Father. &lt;br/&gt;When you became man to set us free &lt;br/&gt;you did not shun the Virgin\'s womb. &lt;br/&gt;You overcame the sting of death &lt;br/&gt;and opened the kingdom of heaven to all believers. &lt;br/&gt;You are seated at God\'s right hand in glory. &lt;br/&gt;We believe that you will come and be our judge. &lt;br/&gt; Come then, Lord, and help your people, &lt;br/&gt; bought with the price of your own blood, &lt;br/&gt; and bring us with your saints &lt;br/&gt; to glory everlasting.</item>


    </string-array>

    <string name="apostlescreed">I believe in God, the Father almighty,&lt;br /&gt;maker of heaven and earth;&lt;br /&gt;I believe in Jesus Christ, his only Son our Lord;&lt;br /&gt;He was conceived by the power of the Holy Spirit,&lt;br /&gt;born of the Virgin Mary,&lt;br /&gt;suffered under Pontius Pilate,&lt;br /&gt;was crucified, died, and buried.&lt;br /&gt;He descended to the dead..&lt;br /&gt;On the third day he rose again.&lt;br /&gt;He ascended into heaven,&lt;br /&gt;and is seated at the right hand of the Father.&lt;br /&gt;He will come again to judge the living and the dead.&lt;br /&gt;I believe in the Holy Spirit,&lt;br /&gt;the holy catholic Church,&lt;br /&gt;the communion of saints,&lt;br /&gt;the forgiveness of sins,&lt;br /&gt;the resurrection of the body,&lt;br /&gt;and the life everlasting. Amen.</string>

    <string name="theprayers_pt1">&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;Officiant:  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;The Lord be with you.</string>
    <string name="theprayers_pt2">&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;People:  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;And with they spirit.</string>
    <string name="theprayers_pt3">&lt;i&gt;&lt;small&gt;Officiant:  &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/i&gt;Let us pray.</string>
    <string name="theprayers_pt4_priest">Our Father, who art in heaven,&lt;br /&gt;hallowed be thy Name,&lt;br /&gt;thy kingdom come,&lt;br /&gt;thy will be done,&lt;br /&gt;on earth as it is in heaven.&lt;br /&gt;Give us this day our daily bread.&lt;br /&gt;And forgive us our trespasses,&lt;br /&gt;as we forgive those who trespass against us.&lt;br /&gt;And lead us not into temptation, &lt;br /&gt;but deliver us from evil.&lt;br /&gt;For thine is the kingdom, and the power, and the glory,&lt;br /&gt;for ever and ever. Amen.</string>
    <string name="theprayers_pt4_other">Our Father in heaven, &lt;br/&gt;  hallowed be your Name, &lt;br/&gt;  your kingdom come, &lt;br/&gt;  your will be done, &lt;br/&gt; on earth as in heaven. &lt;br/&gt;Give us today our daily bread. &lt;br/&gt;Forgive us our sins &lt;br/&gt; as we forgive those &lt;br/&gt; who sin against us. &lt;br/&gt;Save us from the time of trial, &lt;br/&gt; and deliver us from evil. &lt;br/&gt;For the kingdom, the power, &lt;br/&gt; and the glory are yours, &lt;br/&gt; now and for ever. Amen.</string>

    <string name="sufferageA">V. Show us your mercy, O Lord; &lt;br/&gt;R. And grant us your salvation. &lt;br/&gt;V. Clothe your ministers with righteousness; &lt;br/&gt;R. Let your people sing with joy. &lt;br/&gt;V. Give peace, O Lord, in all the world; &lt;br/&gt;R. For only in you can we live in safety.&lt;br/&gt;V. Lord, keep this nation under your care; &lt;br/&gt;R. And guide us in the way of justice and truth. &lt;br/&gt;V. Let your way be known upon earth; &lt;br/&gt;R. Your saving health among all nations. &lt;br/&gt;V. Let not the needy, O Lord, be forgotten; &lt;br/&gt;R. Nor the hope of the poor be taken away. &lt;br/&gt;V. Create in us clean hearts, O God; &lt;br/&gt;R. And sustain us with your Holy Spirit.</string>
    <string name="sufferageB">V. Save your people, Lord, and bless your inheritance; &lt;br/&gt;R. Govern them and uphold them, now and always.&lt;br/&gt;V. Day by day we bless you; &lt;br/&gt;R. We praise your name for ever. &lt;br/&gt;V. Lord, keep us from all sin today; &lt;br/&gt;R. Have mercy upon us, Lord, have mercy. &lt;br/&gt;V. Lord, show us your love and mercy; &lt;br/&gt;R. For we put our trust in you. &lt;br/&gt;V. In you, Lord, is our hope; &lt;br/&gt;R. And we shall never hope in vain.</string>

    <string name="collect_sundays">O God, you make us glad with the weekly remembrance of the glorious resurrection of your Son our Lord: Give us this day such blessing through our worship of you, that the week to come may be spent in your favor; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="collect_fridays">Almighty God, whose most dear Son went not up to joy but first he suffered pain, and entered not into glory before he was crucified: Mercifully grant that we, walking in the way of the cross, may find it none other than the way of life and peace; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="collect_saturdays">Almighty God, who after the creation of the world rested from all your works and sanctified a day of rest for all your creatures: Grant that we, putting away all earthly anxieties, may be duly prepared for the service of your sanctuary, and that our rest here upon earth may be a preparation for the eternal rest promised to your people in heaven; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="collect_renewaloflife">O God, the King eternal, whose light divides the day from the night and turns the shadow of death into the morning: Drive far from us all wrong desires, incline our hearts to keep your law, and guide our feet into the way of peace; that, having done your will with cheerfulness while it was day, we may, when night comes, rejoice to give you thanks; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="collect_peace">O God, the author of peace and lover of concord, to know you is eternal life and to serve you is perfect freedom: Defend us, your humble servants, in all assaults of our enemies; that we, surely trusting in your defense, may not fear the power of any adversaries; through the might of Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="collect_grace">Lord God, almighty and everlasting Father, you have brought us in safety to this new day: Preserve us with your mighty power, that we may not fall into sin, nor be overcome by adversity; and in all we do, direct us to the fulfilling of your purpose; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string name="collect_guidance">Heavenly Father, in you we live and move and have our being: We humbly pray you so to guide and govern us by your Holy Spirit, that in all the cares and occupations of our life we may not forget you, but may remember that we are ever walking in your sight; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</string>
    <string-array name="collect_endings">
        <item>Almighty and everlasting God, by whose Spirit the whole body of your faithful people is governed and sanctified: Receive our supplications and prayers which we offer before you for all members of your holy Church, that in their vocation and ministry they may truly and devoutly serve you; through our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ. Amen.</item>
        <item>O God, you have made of one blood all the peoples of the earth, and sent your blessed Son to preach peace to those who are far off and to those who are near: Grant that people everywhere may seek after you and find you; bring the nations into your fold; pour out your Spirit upon all flesh; and hasten the coming of your kingdom; through Jesus Christ our Lord. Amen.</item>
        <item>Lord Jesus Christ, you stretched out your arms of love on the hard wood of the cross that everyone might come within the reach of your saving embrace: So clothe us in your Spirit that we, reaching forth our hands in love, may bring those who do not know you to the knowledge and love of you; for the honor of your Name. Amen.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="thanksgiving_pt1">Almighty God, Father of all mercies, &lt;br/&gt;we your unworthy servants give you humble thanks &lt;br/&gt;for all your goodness and loving-kindness &lt;br/&gt;to us and to all whom you have made. &lt;br/&gt;We bless you for our creation, preservation, &lt;br/&gt;and all the blessings of this life; &lt;br/&gt;but above all for your immeasurable love &lt;br/&gt;in the redemption of the world by our Lord Jesus Christ; &lt;br/&gt;for the means of grace, and for the hope of glory. &lt;br/&gt;And, we pray, give us such an awareness of your mercies, &lt;br/&gt;that with truly thankful hearts we may show forth your praise, &lt;br/&gt;not only with our lips, but in our lives, &lt;br/&gt;by giving up our selves to your service, &lt;br/&gt;and by walking before you &lt;br/&gt;in holiness and righteousness all our days; &lt;br/&gt;through Jesus Christ our Lord, &lt;br/&gt;to whom, with you and the Holy Spirit, &lt;br/&gt;be honor and glory throughout all ages. Amen.</string>
    <string name="thanksgiving_pt2">Let us bless the Lord.</string>
    <string name="thanksgiving_pt3">&lt;i&gt;Thanks be to God.</string>
    <string-array name="thanksgiving_pt4_chapters">
        <item>2 Corinthians 13:14</item>
        <item>Romans 15:13</item>
        <item>Ephesians 3:20,21</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="thanksgiving_pt4">
        <item>The grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, and the love of God, and the fellowship of the Holy Spirit, be with us all evermore. Amen.</item>
        <item>May the God of hope fill us with all joy and peace in believing through the power of the Holy Spirit. Amen. </item>
        <item>Glory to God whose power, working in us, can do infinitely more than we can ask or imagine: Glory to him from generation to generation in the Church, and in Christ Jesus for ever and ever. Amen.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
