<resources>

    <string name="blank"></string>
    <string name="app_name">Morning Prayer</string>
    <string name="clergy_prompt_text">I AM A:</string>
    <string name="clergy_first">PRIEST</string>
    <string name="clergy_second">OTHER</string>
    <string name="reading_prompt_text">I WANT TO READ:</string>
    <string name="reading_first">JUBILATE</string>
    <string name="reading_second">VENITE</string>
    <string name="collect_prompt_text">I WANT TO COLLECT WITH:</string>
    <string name="thanksgiving_prompt_text">IT IS A TIME OF THANKSGIVING</string>
    <string-array name="collects">
        <item>SUNDAYS</item>
        <item>SATURDAYS</item>
        <item>FRIDAYS</item>
        <item>PEACE</item>
        <item>RENEWAL OF LIFE</item>
        <item>GRACE</item>
        <item>GUIDANCE</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="alleluia">Alleluia</string>
    <string name="opensent">Opening Sentences</string>
    <string name="confofsin">Confession of Sin</string>
    <string name="invandsalt">The Inventory and Psalter</string>
    <string name="lesson">The Lessons</string>
    <string name="creed">The Apostles\' Creed</string>
    <string name="prayers">The Prayers</string>
    <string name="collectday">The Collect of the Day</string>
    <string name="thanksgiving">The General Thanksgiving</string>

    <string name="silencekneeling">Silence may be kept, all kneeling</string>
    <string name="silence">Silence may be kept</string>
    <string name="prieststand">The Priest alone stands and says</string>
    <string name="stand">All stand</string>
    <string name="remainkneeling">Remaining Kneeling</string>
    <string name="togetherstand">Officiant and people together, all standing</string>
    <string name="togetherkneel">Officiant and people together, all kneeling</string>
    <string name="officiantandpeople">Officiant and People</string>
    <string name="officiantsays">The Officiant says to the people</string>

    <string-array name="openingadvent_chapters">
        <item>Mark 13:55, 36</item>
        <item>Isaiah 40:3</item>
        <item>Isaiah 40:5</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingadvent">
        <item>Watch, for you known not when the master of the house will come, in the evening, or at midnight, or at cockcrow, or in my morning; lest he come suddenly and find you asleep.</item>
        <item>In the wilderness prepare the way of the Lord, make straight in the desert a highway for our God.</item>
        <item>The glory of the Lord shall be revealed, and all flesh shall see it together.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingchristmas_chapters">
        <item>Luke 2:10, 11</item>
        <item>Revelation 21:3</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingchristmas">
        <item>Behold, I bring you good news of a great joy, which will come to all the people; for unto you is born this day in the city of David, a Savior, who is Christ the Lord.</item>
        <item>Behold, the dwelling of God is the mankind. He will dwell with them, and they shall be his people, and God himself will be with them, and be their God.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingepiphany_chapters">
        <item>Isaiah 60:3</item>
        <item>Isaiah 49:6b</item>
        <item>Malachi 1:11</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingepiphany">
        <item>Nations shall come to your light, and kings to the brightness of your rising.</item>
        <item>I will give you as a light to the nations, that my salvation may reach to the end of the earth.</item>
        <item>From the rising of the sun to its setting my Name shall be great among the nations, and in every place incense shall be offered to my Name, and a pure offering: for my Name shall be great among the nations, says the Lord of hosts.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openinglent_chapters">
        <item>I John 1:8, 9</item>
        <item>Joel 2:13</item>
        <item>Luke 15:18, 19</item>
        <item>Daniel 9:9, 10</item>
        <item>Mark 8:34</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openinglent">
        <item>If we say we have no sin, we deceive ourselves, and the tr uth is not in us; but if we confess our sins, God who is faithful and just, will forgive our sins and cleanse us from all unrighteousness.</item>
        <item>Rend your hearts and not your garments. Return to the Lord your God, for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love, and repents of evil.</item>
        <item>I will arise and go to my father, and I will say to him, "Father, I have sinned against heaven, and before you; I am no longer worthy to be called your son."</item>
        <item>To the Lord our God belong mercy and forgiveness, because we have rebelled against him and have not obeyed the voice of the Lord our God by following his laws which he set before us.</item>
        <item>Jesus said, "If anyone will come after me, let him deny himself, and take up his cross, and follow me."</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingholyweek_chapters">
        <item>Isaiah 53:6</item>
        <item>Lamentations 1:12</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingholyweek">
        <item>All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the Lord has laid on him the iniquity of us all.</item>
        <item>Is it nothing to you, all you who pass by? Look and see if there is any sorrow like my sorrow which was brought upon me, whom the Lord hath afflicted.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="openingeasterasc_chapters">
        <item>Psalm 118:24</item>
        <item>1 Corinthians 15:57</item>
        <item>Colossians 3:1</item>
        <item>Hebrews 9:24</item>
        <item>Acts 1:8</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingeasterasc">
        <item>On this day the Lord has acted; we will rejoice and be glad in it.</item>
        <item>Thanks be to God, who gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ.</item>
        <item>If then you have been raised with Christ, seek the things that are above, where Christ is, seated at the right hand of God.</item>
        <item>Christ has entered, not into a sanctuary made with hands, a copy of true one, but into heaven itself, now to appear in the presence of God on our behalf.</item>
        <item>You shall receive power when the Holy Ghost has come upon you; and you shall be my witness in Jerusalem, and in all Judea, and Samaria, and to the ends of the earth.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="openingeasterasc_pt1">Alleluia! Christ is risen.</string>
    <string name="openingeasterasc_pt2">The Lord is risen indeed. Alleluia!</string>

    <string name="revelation4_8">Revelation 4:8</string>
    <string name="openingtrinity">Holy, holy, holy is the Lord God Almighty, who was, and is, and is to come.</string>

    <string-array name="openingsaint_chapters">
        <item>Colossians 1:12</item>
        <item>Ephesians 2:19</item>
        <item>Psalm 19:4</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openingsaint">
        <item>We give thanks to the Father, who has made us worthy to share in the inheritance of the saints in light.</item>
        <item>You are no longer strangers and sojourners, but fellow citizens with the saints and members of the household of God.</item>
        <item>Their sound has gone out into all lands, and their message to the ends of the world.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="psalm105_1">Psalm 105:1</string>
    <string name="openingthanksgiving">O give thanks to the Lord, and call upon his Name; make known his deeds among the peoples.</string>

    <string-array name="openinganytime_chapters">
        <item>Philippians 1:2</item>
        <item>Psalm 122:1</item>
        <item>Psalm 19:14</item>
        <item>Psalm 43:3</item>
        <item>Habakkuk 2:20</item>
        <item>John 4:23</item>
        <item>Isaiah 57:15</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="openinganytime">
        <item>Grace to you and peace from God our Father and from the Lord Jesus Christ.</item>
        <item>I was glad when they said to me, "Let us go to the house of the Lord."</item>
        <item>Let the words of my mouth and the meditation of my heart be acceptable in your sight, O Lord, my strength and my redeemer.</item>
        <item>Send out your light and your truth, that they may lead me, and bring me to your holy hill and to your dwelling.</item>
        <item>The Lord is in his holy temple; let all the earth keep silence before him.</item>
        <item>The hour is coming, and now is, when the true worshipers will worship the Father in spirit and in truth, for such the Father seeks to worship him.</item>
        <item>Thus says the high and lofty One who inhabits eternity, whose name is Holy, "I dwell in the high and holy place and also with the one who has a contrite and humble spirit, to revive the spirit of the humble and to revive the heart of the contrite."</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="confessionofsin_pt1_priest">
        <item>Dearly beloved, we have come together in the presence of Almighty God our heavenly Father, to set forth his praise, to hear his holy Word, and to ask, for ourselves and on behalf of others, those things that are necessary for our life and our salvation. And so that we may prepare ourselves in heart and mind to worship him, let us kneel in silence, and with penitent and obedient hearts confess our sins, that we may obtain forgiveness by his infinite goodness and mercy.</item>
        <item>Let us confess our sins against God and our neighbor.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt2_priest">Most merciful God, we confess that we have sinned against you in thought, word, and deed, by what we have done, and by what we have left undone. We have not loved you with our whole heart; that we may delight in your will, and walk in your ways, to the glory of your Name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt3_priest">Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through our Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life. <i>Amen.</i></string>
    <string-array name="confessionofsin_pt1_other">
        <item>Dearly beloved, we have come together in the presence of Almighty God your heavenly Father, to set forth his praise, to hear his holy Word, and to ask, for ourselves and on behalf of others, those things that are necessary for your life and your salvation. And so that we may prepare ourselves in heart and mind to worship him, let you kneel in silence, and with penitent and obedient hearts confess your sins, that we may obtain forgiveness by his infinite goodness and mercy.</item>
        <item>Let you confess your sins against God and your neighbor.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt2_other">Most merciful God, we confess that we have sinned against you in thought, word, and deed, by what we have done, and by what we have left undone. We have not loved you with your whole heart; that we may delight in your will, and walk in your ways, to the glory of your Name. Amen.</string>
    <string name="confessionofsin_pt3_other">Almighty God have mercy on you, forgive you all your sins through your Lord Jesus Christ, strengthen you in all goodness, and by the power of the Holy Spirit keep you in eternal life. <i>Amen.</i></string>

    <string name="invandsalt_pt1"><i>Officiant</i>: Lord, open our lips.</string>
    <string name="invandsalt_pt2"><i>People</i>: And our mouth shall proclaim your praise.</string>
    <string name="invandsalt_pt3_lent">Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Amen.</string>
    <string name="invandsalt_pt3">Glory to the Father, and to the Son, and to the Holy Spirit: as it was in the beginning, is now, and will be for ever. Alleluia.</string>

    <string name="jubilate_title">Jubilate</string>
    <string name="psalm100">Psalm 100</string>
    <string name="jubilate">Be joyful in the Lord, all you lands;&lt;br /&gt;serve the Lord with gladness&lt;br /&gt;and come before his presence with a song.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Know this: The Lord himself is God;&lt;br /&gt;he himself has made us, and we are his;&lt;br /&gt;we are his people and the sheep of his pasture.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Enter his gates with thanksgiving;&lt;br /&gt;go into his courts with praise;&lt;br /&gt;give thanks to him and call upon his Name.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the Lord is good;&lt;br /&gt;his mercy is everlasting;&lt;br /&gt;and his faithfulness endures from age to age.</string>
    <string name="venite_title">Venite</string>
    <string name="psalm95_1">Psalm 95:1-7</string>
    <string name="venite">Come, let us sing to the Lord;&lt;br /&gt;let us shout for joy to the Rock of our salvation.&lt;br /&gt;Let us come before his presence with thanksgiving&lt;br /&gt;and raise a loud shout to him with psalms.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;For the Lord is a great God,&lt;br /&gt;and a great King above all gods.&lt;br /&gt;In his hand are the caverns of the earth,&lt;br /&gt;and the heights of the hills are his also.&lt;br /&gt;The sea is his, for he made it,&lt;br /&gt;and his hands have molded the dry land.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Come, let us bow down, and bend the knee,&lt;br /&gt;and kneel before the Lord our Maker.&lt;br /&gt;For he is our God,&lt;br /&gt;and we are the people of his pasture and the sheep of his hand.&lt;br /&gt;Oh, that today you would hearken to his voice!</string>

</resources>
